So now we have to introduce our ad item feature into our application.
But let's take a look at it in our final application so we can understand what it needs to do so we
can figure out the right strategy to approach building it.
Well first we know that each item has a hover effect and when we click Add to cart it add that to this
cart if the item already exists it will increase the count on it.
But if it's something new it will add a new item here if we go to checkout we notice that almost the
same component is displayed using the same data except this one can modify the quantity of those items
but first let's just build out the basics of this feature while thinking about how we can reuse this
capability because it seems like it's a very similar Add To Cart feature which pretty much does the
same thing as hitting this icon.
We're still adding these items to the cart and increasing the quantity but the first thing we should
tackle is just converting our collection item to have this hover effect and then set up our redux files
for our cart to be able to store our items so let's go back to our application and let's first modify
this component
what we need to do is actually go to our custom button component and we are going to first need to invert
the colors based on a property just like we did when we added this custom class of Google sign in and
those Google sign in styles.
So what we'll do is we'll add an inverted prop that does the exact same thing as our Google sign in
except instead of Google sign and we will say if inverted is true then add the inverted class and then
in our custom button we will add in this inverted class.
What it will do is the opposite of what our regular styling on our custom button is.
So if it's inverted.
Those are the styles.
Right.
Because when we hover we we flip the colors in our normal button.
But if it's not then we want
the same color and similarly if we hover.
Then it switches to what our normal button styles are like with the border of non now that we have our
inverted button.
We just need to import this into our component so one more thing we want to add is just something to
make sure that our text is always aligned and if we do display flex and justified content center anything
in our button will always be centered inside of our element now let's go to our collection item and
in our collection item what we are going to add is our custom button
from our component custom button and we're just going to put it after our collection for
an inside will be our text of add to cart and what we will also add is that inverted key and if we look
we should at least see the button.
There it is.
Now we do need to add some styles to our custom button that are only unique to our collection item component.
So what we can do is we can go into our collection item styles and we can just manually add them here
so we can say that they're on our custom button we or first set the width to 80 percent will also set
the opacity to zero point seven.
We want a position of absolute because we want to always to be absolutely positioned at the bottom of
our total height.
And that will be a value of top 255 pixel we'll also need to add a position relative value to our collection
item and now if we look we'll see that our button is positioned inside of our collection item but what
else we're going to need to do is add that hover animation because by default our custom buttons should
be hidden.
So let's do display none and then add our hover feature on our collection item itself.
And what we'll do is we'll first make our own image opacity set to zero point eight and we'll also make
sure that our custom button gets an opacity value of zero point eight five.
Also need to add our display flex so that we display it and now if we see we have are hovering feature
on our collection item so those are a bit of style changes just to make it so that our application now
can support that add item feature that we're about to implement.